<network><node name="TCGA"><desc>An NIH program to study cancer</desc></node><node name="MAPK"><desc>A family of kinases</desc></node><node name="NIH"><desc>The largest biomedical research funding agency</desc></node><node name="NCI"><desc>A NIH institute for studying cancer</desc></node><node name="KEA"><desc>Enrichment analysis tool for kinase</desc></node><node name="ChEA"><desc>Enrichment analysis tool for transcription factors</desc></node><node name="LINCS"><desc>A NIH common fund program</desc></node><node name="SILAC"><desc>Method to measure post-translational modifications</desc></node><node name="GEO"><desc>repository for large datasets</desc></node><node name="PPI"><desc>Interactions between proteins</desc></node><node name="PWM"><desc>Consensus sequence motifs</desc></node><node name="PTM"><desc>changes on protein sites</desc></node><node name="OMIM"><desc>database about disease genes</desc></node><node name="PLOS"><desc>A family of journals</desc></node><node name="BMC"><desc>A family of scientific journals</desc></node><node name="DEG"><desc>The genes that expressed in different levels from one condition to another</desc></node><node name="MDS"><desc>An algorithm that calculates coordinates of data points based on their pair-wise distances</desc></node><node name="PCA"><desc>An algorithm that transforms coordinates of data points in a higher dimensional space to a lower one</desc></node><node name="GSEA"><desc>A method to extract the biological knowledge from a list of genes</desc></node><node name="API"><desc>An interface from which interactions with a program can be made</desc></node><node name="GO"><desc>A hierachical rerpresentation of biological knowedge on gene sets</desc></node><node name="COSMIC"><desc>A resource for Somatic Mutations in Cancer</desc></node><node name="SIDER"><desc>sider effect resources</desc></node><node name="GWAS"><desc>Population-based analysis of mutation-phenotype correlations</desc></node><node name="LCMS"><desc>"Experimental technique for analyzing complex chemical mixtures. For example, mixtures of proteins."</desc></node><node name="CRISPR"><desc>A genetic technique that can be used to edit genes in many different biological models. For example changing specific base pairs or deleting specific genes.</desc></node><node name="GFP"><desc>A green-glowing protein originally found in jellyfish but now widely used in biological experiments as a reporter protein.</desc></node><node name="SVM"><desc>A supervised statistical method that uses separating hyperplanes and kernels in higher dimensions.</desc></node><node name="ENCODE"><desc>Catalogue of functional elements of the human geneome</desc></node><node name="BLAST"><desc>Algorithms for comparing sequence data</desc></node><node name="RPPA "><desc>A protein array designed as a micro- or nano-scaled dot-blot platform that allows measurement of protein expression levels in a large number of biological samples simultaneously in a quantitative manner when high-qualityantibodies are available.</desc></node><node name="GCP"><desc>A mass spectrometry-based assay to identify and quantify post-translational modifications on histone proteins from bulk chromatin.</desc></node><node name="ATAC-seq"><desc>"A method for mapping chromatin accessibility genome-wide. This method probes DNA accessibility with hyperactive Tn5 transposase, which inserts sequencing adapters into accessible regions of chromatin"</desc></node><node name="MEMA"><desc>One of the most widely used of all synthetic cell culture media originally developed by Harry Eagle. Used in LINCS project</desc></node><node name="iPSC"><desc>A type ofpluripotent stem cell that can be generated directly from adult cells.</desc></node><node name="SNP"><desc>"A DNA sequence variation occurring commonly within a population (e.g. 1%) in which a single nucleotide-A,T,C or G in the genome (or other shared sequence) differs between members of a biological species or pairedchromosomes"</desc></node></network>