<network><node name="ADMET"><desc>_______ stands for absorption, distribution, metabolism, excretion and toxicity. _______ assays are performed for verifying the bio-availability,  toxicity, metabolic stability, and drug-drug interaction potential of drugs: They quantify absorption of drugs in the intestine which is dependent on their solubility; distribution which ascertains their binding to plasma proteins, central nervous system penetration; metabolism where the in vivo clearance is monitored; and finally, toxicity in terms of inhibition of liver cytochrome p450 enzymes or hERG which could cause drug-drug interactions and cardiac arrhythmias, respectively.</desc></node><node name="confirmatory assay"><desc>Assay performed to confirm activity of compounds identified in the primary screen.  It can be performed as replicate measurements at a single screening concentration or as concentration-response assay.</desc></node><node name="primary assay"><desc>The first assay performed in a in a screening campaign. The purpose of the _______ is to identify hits, which are potentially biologically active chemical entities. Generally in this assay, the perturbagens are tested at a single concentration with only one measurement. It is followed by a confirmatory screen, which can be run at a single concentration with multiple replicates or as concentration-response assay.</desc></node><node name="secondary assay"><desc>Additional assays following the confirmatory stage to confirm the biological activity of chemical entities via a different type of assay or to eliminate certain active compounds based on their mechanism of action, toxicity or activity profile.  _______s can also include selectivity and specificity assays.</desc></node><node name="ADMET"><desc>_______ stands for absorption, distribution, metabolism, excretion and toxicity. _______ assays are performed for verifying the bio-availability,  toxicity, metabolic stability, and drug-drug interaction potential of drugs: They quantify absorption of drugs in the intestine which is dependent on their solubility; distribution which ascertains their binding to plasma proteins, central nervous system penetration; metabolism where the in vivo clearance is monitored; and finally, toxicity in terms of inhibition of liver cytochrome p450 enzymes or hERG which could cause drug-drug interactions and cardiac arrhythmias, respectively.</desc></node><node name="confirmatory assay"><desc>Assay performed to confirm activity of compounds identified in the primary screen.  It can be performed as replicate measurements at a single screening concentration or as concentration-response assay.</desc></node><node name="primary assay"><desc>The first assay performed in a in a screening campaign. The purpose of the _______ is to identify hits, which are potentially biologically active chemical entities. Generally in this assay, the perturbagens are tested at a single concentration with only one measurement. It is followed by a confirmatory screen, which can be run at a single concentration with multiple replicates or as concentration-response assay.</desc></node><node name="secondary assay"><desc>Additional assays following the confirmatory stage to confirm the biological activity of chemical entities via a different type of assay or to eliminate certain active compounds based on their mechanism of action, toxicity or activity profile.  _______s can also include selectivity and specificity assays.</desc></node><node name="protein-small molecule interaction assay"><desc>It is an interaction between a protein (e.g., receptor, transcription factor) and small molecule (e.g., hormone, organic compound with a low molecular weight (&lt;800 Da)).</desc></node><node name="oligonucleotide array"><desc>Oligonucleotides are immobilized by spotting on a solid support, such as a glass slide. They are hybridized with labeled nucleic acids from a sample and the signals measured, which reflects the composition of the sample nucleic acids. This is performed to either quantify gene expression or genomic profiling to understand genetic variation in humans.</desc></node><node name="metal ion redistribution assay"><desc>Metal ions such as copper, iron, magnesium and zinc are transported between different cellular compartments to bring about specific functions. This is regulated by their influx and efflux across membranes, which could occur either by passive diffusion or active transport.</desc></node><node name="screening campaign"><desc>_______ incudes a sequence of (assay) experiments performed to identify a compound (or a series of compounds) with a specific function and it is desirable to have a known mechanism of action. It includes primary (screening at single concentration), secondary, and confirmatory (dose response) screens, structure activity relationship (SAR) studies, lead optimization, etc.</desc></node><node name="endpoint assay"><desc>Reported results do not have a time dimension, but represent a static response. This does not mean that the result is indepent from the time of measurement, such as cell viablity at 12, 24 or 72h where the time point is associated metadata.</desc></node><node name="kinetic assay"><desc>The measurements and reported outcome / result of the _______ quantify a change / response over a time course; the reported result has a time component, for example a reaction constant or rate.  This is in contrast to an endpoint that does not have a time dimension, but is associated with a time point as metadata, such as cell viablity at 12, 24 or 72 hs, but not the speed with which the cells propargate or die.</desc></node><node name="small molecule array"><desc>Small molecules which are either natural or synthetic are immobilized by robotic printing on a solid support, such as a functionalized glass slide. Protein targets either purified or from a lysate are hybridized to the immobilized small molecules in an attempt to identify the natural ligands for proteins, and also molecules that could regulate their function.</desc></node><node name="lysate array"><desc>This contains complex samples, such as cell or tissue lysates, spotted on an array surface and interrogated with antibodies.</desc></node><node name="selectivity assay"><desc>Assay employed to elucidate the specificity of biologically active chemical entities towards one or more targets that are (closely) related to the (intended) primary target.</desc></node><node name="analytical array"><desc>In this method, antibodies or peptides are spotted on a support to be hybridized to analytes in complex mixtures of proteins.</desc></node><node name="purified protein array"><desc>In this method, many different purified proteins are spotted on a support, and used to assay biochemical functions such as protein-protein, protein-DNA, protein-small molecule interactions and enzyme activity.</desc></node><node name="nucleic acid array"><desc>Nucleic acids, either DNA or RNA are immobilized by spotting on a solid support such as a glass slide. They are hybridized with labeled nucleic acids from a sample and the signals measured, which reflects the composition of the sample nucleic acids. This is performed to quantify gene expression under various situations, e.g. diseases, development, etc.</desc></node><node name="protein array"><desc>This includes spotting purified proteins, cell or tissue lysates, antibodies, or peptides in order to quantify the proteome, or study protein-protein, protein-DNA, protein-small molecule interactions and enzyme activity. </desc></node><node name="gene array"><desc>_______s include a collection of gene-specific nucleic acids that have been placed at defined locations on a solid support, either by spotting or direct synthesis. Labeled nucleic acids from a sample are hybridized with target genes on the array and the signals measured, which reflects the composition of the sample nucleic acids.</desc></node><node name="microplate"><desc>The assay is performed in a _______, which can either be 96 well, 384 well, or 1536 well plates.</desc></node><node name="assay footprint"><desc>This describes the physical format such as plate density in which an assay is performed, which is generally a microplate format, but can also be an array format.</desc></node><node name="summary assay"><desc>It is a PubChem-specific assay stage. A _______ references and summarizes the assays in PubChem that correspond to a screening campaign or a probe development project.</desc></node><node name="lead optimization assay"><desc>Assays performed in the lead optimization stage. They are typically concentration-response high quality assays. They can involve a number of different assays depending on the required profile of the desired lead compound.</desc></node><node name="vial"><desc>_______s are small containers that are used in biological measurements, including scintillation counting.</desc></node><node name="cuvette"><desc>_______s are used to measure absorbance or fluorescence in a spectrophotometer or fluorimeter, respectively using either plastic, glass or quartz _______s.</desc></node><node name="assay repository"><desc>It is the repository (database) in which the assay was deposited, e.g., PubChem, ChEMBL, etc.</desc></node><node name="PubChem"><desc>_______ (http://_______.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov) is a public database that contains high throughput screening (HTS) data, where the assays are performed to identify small molecules effective at modulating a given biological process or disease state. The bioactivity results in _______ are contributed by several organizations, with the majority of data coming from the screening center network under the NIH Molecular Libraries Program (MLP).</desc></node><node name="ChEMBL"><desc>It is a public database that contains structure&#8211;activity relationship (SAR) data curated from the medicinal chemistry literature.</desc></node><node name="PDSP"><desc>It is a public database that contains screening data of novel psychoactive compounds for pharmacological and functional activity.</desc></node><node name="compound toxicity assay"><desc>This assay is performed to identify compounds that have an ability to kill the cells (cytotoxic).</desc></node><node name="parental cell line assay"><desc>This assay is performed with the unmodified or parental cell line instead of the one modified with a DNA construct that was used in primary or confirmatory assays.</desc></node><node name="counter screening assay"><desc>An assay run to eliminate those hits from the primary and confirmatory assay stages that are not of interest, i.e. do not act via the MMOA of interest; for example compounds that are assay artifacts (e.g. fluorescent), promiscuously active, toxic. </desc></node><node name="alternate confirmatory assay"><desc>An assay using orthogonal assay design / technology run to confirm the identified hits from the primary and confirmatory assay stages.</desc></node><node name="variant construct assay"><desc>This assay is performed with a different DNA construct than that was used in primary or confirmatory assays to modify a cell line.</desc></node><node name="alternate target assay"><desc>This assay is performed with a different but a related target (usually from the same protein family) than that was tested in primary or confirmatory assays, e.g., SIP1 instead of SIP3.</desc></node><node name="alternate organism assay"><desc>This assay is performed with a different organism than that was tested in primary or confirmatory assays.</desc></node><node name="compound fluorescence assay"><desc>This assay is performed to identify compounds that have a property of auto-fluorescence.</desc></node><node name="compound aggregation assay"><desc>This assay is performed to identify compounds that have a propensity to aggregate.</desc></node><node name="compound redox activity assay"><desc>This assay is performed to identify compounds with redox (reducing or oxidizing) activity.</desc></node><node name="gene expression assay"><desc>This assay quantifies the expression level of the entire gene pool in a cell or a subpopulation (e.g. tissue-specific gene expression, kinases) using either microarray, bead method, RNASeq, or reporter gene method.</desc></node><node name="assay readout parameter"><desc>_______ is the outcome of image analysis and is most often a calculated value.
This includes 'parameters', such as 'intensity', 'count', 'morphology', etc which are all dependent on phenotype, e.g., intensity and count (number of bright spots) are a result of the amount of gene expression, and morphology is dependent on morphological phenotype, which is detected by the expression of a marker.</desc></node><node name="counting parameter"><desc>_______ is an output of the device measuring the number of the subject.</desc></node><node name="densitometric parameter"><desc>_______ is an output of the device that is the density value of the subject by measuring the amount of light or fluorescence detected on the image.</desc></node><node name="intensity parameter"><desc>_______ is an output of the device measuring the intensity value for the light signal of the subject.</desc></node><node name="morphometric parameter"><desc>_______ is an output of image analysis measuring a structure, a concept that encompasses size and shape of the subject (cells, organisms).</desc></node><node name="binding assay"><desc>It is performed to quantify the interactions between two molecules, e.g. small molecule-protein, protein-protein, protein-DNA, etc.</desc></node><node name="protein-protein interaction assay"><desc>It is performed to quantify the interactions between two protein molecules, using methods such as protein fragment complementation assay, immunoassay, radioligand binding, etc.</desc></node><node name="cell morphology assay"><desc>It reports the size and shape of cells and organelles (phenotype). These are detected by microscopy.</desc></node><node name="cell motility assay"><desc>It is performed to measure the movement of cells and organelles (phenotype).  These are detected by microscopy.</desc></node><node name="enzyme activity assay"><desc>It is used to measure the effect of a perturbagen on the enzyme activity, which can be measured either directly or coupled to a secondary signal. </desc></node><node name="transcriptional response profiling assay"><desc>This assay quantifies the expression level of the entire gene pool in a cell or a subpopulation (e.g. tissue-specific gene expression, kinases) using a bead-based method.</desc></node><node name="membrane potential assay"><desc>This reports the membrane potential of a cell by using electrophysiological techniques or by staining with dyes whose binding is dependent on the membrane potential.</desc></node><node name="ion channel assay"><desc>_______s are performed in electrically active cells: neurons, muscle, and endocrine cells.</desc></node><node name="protein folding assay"><desc>This assay quantifies the protein folding/conformation using technologies, such as nuclear magnetic resonance, circular dichroism are used to determine the protein folding/conformation.</desc></node><node name="redistribution assay"><desc>It is performed to measure the redistribution of organelles and molecules within the cell (proteins, second messengers, metal ions, dyes, etc. ). This is visualized by microscopy. </desc></node><node name="rna splicing assay"><desc>This assay quantifies the amount of a mature transcript that is produced after splicing. Splicing is a modification of an mRNA intermediate after transcription, in which introns are removed and exons are joined. It can be detected by several methods, namely, the use of a reporter gene, RNA-Seq, specialiez microarrays, etc. </desc></node><node name="sensitizer assay"><desc>This assay allows the identification of new drugs that sensitize or desensitize the sensitivity of a cell to its signaling molecule (e.g calcium, light). The perturbagen has the role 'sensitizer' in this assay. </desc></node><node name="signal transduction assay"><desc>This assay measures one of the series of events that are downstream to the receipt of a chemical signal at the cell&#8217;s surface, namely, formation of cyclic AMP, activation of kinase/ transcription factor, cytokine secretion, etc., which will result in a specific cellular activity, such as cell division, cell elongation, etc.</desc></node><node name="cytokine secretion assay"><desc>It measures the types and amounts of cytokines that are released as the consequence of a signaling event. Cytokines can be quantitated using ELISA-based kits, PCR array, etc.</desc></node><node name="posttranslation modification assay"><desc>This assay quantifies the modification that a protein can undergo after it is synthesized by translation. E.g. phosphorylation, acetylation, etc. The modification status is detected by one of several methods such as using modification specific antibodies followed by western blotting, imaging; mass spectrometry, etc.</desc></node><node name="phosphorylation assay"><desc>This assay quantifies the phosphorylation levels of a protein. The phosphorylation status is detected by one of several methods: using phosphorylation specific antibodies followed by western blotting or imaging, mass spectrometry, etc.</desc></node><node name="reporter gene assay"><desc>_______ measures the gene expression from a reporter gene. The reporter gene is inserted under the control of a foreign promoter or an artificial regulatory element of interest. Reporters include luciferase, beta galactosidase, beta lactamase, chloramphenicol acetyl transferase, or a fluorescent protein.</desc></node><node name="second messenger assay"><desc>This assay quantifies the second messengers (calcium, cAMP, cGMP) produced in the cell as a result of a signaling event.</desc></node><node name="transporter assay"><desc>This assay quantifies the activity of a transporter that carries proteins, cofactors, ions, drugs, etc. across the cell membranes. Fluorescence-conjugated dyes or radiolabeled ligands are used to quantitate the various molecular entities that are being transported.</desc></node><node name="cell viability assay"><desc>This assay type measures the cellular state of living or dying by measuring an indicator of life or death. Cell life indicators include ATP content, cell number, dehydrogenase activity, DNA content, esterase activity, mitochondrial membrane potential, membrane integrity, and protease activity. Cell death indicators include caspase activity, chromatin condensation, and phospholipid redistribution.</desc></node><node name="protein-turnover assay"><desc>This assay quantifies the protein turnover, which is a natural phenomenon in healthy cells, but becomes aberrant in diseased cells. The protein that is needed to be degraded first undergoes ubiquitinated. Ubiquitinated proteins are degraded in the proteasome complex. The protein degradation is quantitated by using reporters, such as green fluorescent protein as proteasome substrates.  </desc></node></network>